# **Daniel Jones**

Date of Birth: 10-08-1992 19 Brecon Crescent Ingleby Barwick Stockton-On-Tees TS17 5DA Tel.07399130474 danny.jones3926@hotmail.com

#### **Profile**

I have previously served 5 years in the British Army, I worked as a mechanical fitter/ HGV driver in The Royal Engineers. Having vast knowledge working on all types of machinery, generators, vehicles in all aspects of terrain. Since leaving the military in 2014 I have worked as a HGV Class 1 & 2 Driver experiencing the different types of vehicles and also the loads I have been transporting. I've taken a vast interest in the wind industry, where I hope my latest qualifications will be beneficial and lead me into the wind industry.

I Studied a level 2 diploma in safe working practices in the wind industry at Maersk training Newcastle. Which has giving me a vast knowledge of the way the renewable industry works and the technical engineering that's involved in maintaining a wind farm.

With my mechanical background and level 2 diploma in safe working practices in the wind industry, I will have gained the knowledge needed and have all the confidence in the world to thrive as a technician in the business.

# **Industry Certification**

- GWO Working at Height
- GWO Sea Survival
- GWO First Aid
- GWO Fire Awareness
- GWO Manual Handling
- CCNSG Passport
- High Risk Confined Space & Rescue
- Offshore Medical
- MJI 10, 18 and 19
- BPFA Foundation Course In Working Safely With Hydraulic
  - **Hoses and Connectors**
- IRATA level 1 Rope Access

# **Work Experience**

January 2023 - Present

Wind Turbine BOP Technician / Rope Access Technician - Special Marine Consultants

- Stat Inspection
- Hydraulic Torque, Tensioning and Tightening of bolts
- Painting
- Lifting & Rigging
- Painting
- Laddering
- Mechanical preparation of steelwork
- Tower inspection & repairs
- Confined space entry

April 2022 - January 2023

Rope Access Technician Level 1 - Absass Ltd

- Chimney Repairs
- Hydraulic Torque, Tensioning and Tightening of bolts
- Chimney Inspections
- Roof repairs
- Painting
- Laddering
- Mechanical preparation of steelwork
- Cooling tower inspection & repairs
- Working knowledge of motors and cradles.
- Ensure 3 points of contact at all times working at height
- Ensure all painting and maintenance work is carried as per company specification

## January 2022 - April 2022

## Rope Access Technician Level 1 - Zenith Structural Access

- Chimney Repairs
- Hydraulic Torque, Tensioning and Tightening of bolts
- Chimney Inspections
- Roof repairs
- Painting
- Laddering
- Mechanical preparation of steelwork
- Cooling tower inspection & repairs
- Working knowledge of motors and cradles.
- Ensure 3 points of contact at all times working at height
- Ensure all painting and maintenance work is carried as per company specification

#### June 2021 - December 2021

## Rope Access Technician Level 1 - Syntex Engineering

- Chimney Repairs
- Hydraulic Torque, Tensioning and Tightening of bolts
- Chimney Inspections
- Roof repairs
- Painting
- Laddering
- Mechanical preparation of steelwork
- Cooling tower inspection & repairs
- Working knowledge of motors and cradles.

- Ensure 3 points of contact at all times working at height
- Ensure all painting and maintenance work is carried as per company specification

## February 2021 - June 2021

Rope Access Bolting Technician Level 1 - Stone Technical Services - Uk National

- Chimney Repairs
- Hydraulic Torque, Tensioning and Tightening of bolts
- Chimney Inspections
- Roof repairs
- Painting
- Laddering
- Mechanical preparation of steelwork
- Ensure 3 points of contact at all times working at height
- Ensure all painting and maintenance work is carried as per company specification

## October 2019 - February 2021

Rope Access Technician Level 1 - Total Solutions - Hinkley Point A

- Ensure netting is installed and replaced correctly
- Glass window installation and replacement
- Aid climbing
- Painting
- Mechanical preparation of steelwork
- Ensure 3 points of contact at all times working at height
- Ensure all painting and maintenance work is carried as per company specification.

#### March 2019 - October 2019

Wind Turbine Installation Technician - Enercon - Tralorg Wind Farm, Girvan

- Mechanical preparation of steelwork.
- Ensure painting work is carried out to company specification
- Ensure bolt tightening, tensioning and torquing are safely carried out.
- Ensure all pieces of the tower are correct as state manufacturing specification
- Ensure rigging is complete and crane is signed off safely and correctly

## November 2018 - March 2019

Rope Access Technician Level 1 – Proteq (Northern) Limited - London Waterloo

- Mechanical preparation of steelwork.
- Use and safe working of UHP jet washing.
- Ensure bolt tightening, tensioning and torquing are safely carried out.
- Ensure all painting work is carried to company specification

#### March 2018 - October 2018

Multi Skilled Bolt Technician - CWind, Amrumbank Project, Cuxhaven Germany

- Ensure that plant and machinery is maintained.
- Ensure bolt tightening duties are carried out to company specification.
- Ensure bolt tensioning duties are carried out to company specification.
- Ensure health and safety regulations are not compromised.
- Ensure bolt torquing duties are carried out to company specification.

# January 2009 - October 2014

## Mechanical Fitter/Driver Royal Engineers, British Army, England

- Working knowledge of diesel and petrol engines, generators, pumps and vehicle/plant transmission systems.
- Stripping and rebuilding equipment, replacing mechanical seals, oil changes and top ups.

- Understanding of engineer drawings and health and safety regulations.
- Maintain, repair and install mechanical equipment on various asset types
- Be able to swiftly and comprehensively fault find, rectify problems on mechanical equipment including sewage pumps and valves and associated pipe work, air blower, waste water inlet screens.
- Identify problematic plant and the subsequent faults and to take part In finding efficient solutions to return work back to working order.
- Maintaining and conducting first inspection on vehicles to make sure they are roadworthy and fit for purpose.
- Adhering to drivers hours regulations
- Accustomed to driving in Convoy, maintain safe brake safety distance.

# **Education/Training**

• Level 2 diploma in safe working practices in the wind industry, Maersk training centre, Newcastle, England.